HITESH SAKAMURI

+91 9704330358

Bengaluru, India

linkedin.com/in/hitesh-sakamuri

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a software Engineer experienced with React JS, Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js and HTML/CSS. Over the course of my career, I've also worked with Java, MySQL. I have a passion for user-friendly design and I love writing clean and maintainable code, working with people, and learning new things along the way. For fun, I enjoy traveling, music, photography, and reading books.

SKILLS

- React JS
- Angular
- Node.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML, CSS
- MongoDB
- Java
- MySQL
- Git
- Figma

EDUCATION

Sree Vidyanikethan Engineering College

Tirupati • 01/2019

Bachelor of Technology - BTech: Electronics and Communications Engineering

Score: 8.3/10

WORK HISTORY

Cognizant - Software Engineer 05/2019 - Current

Project Experience:

Aflac[11/2021 - Current]

- Actively involved in enhancing the policy purchase platforms [Sales Portal, Agent Portal] through which customer can purchase a supplementary insurance policy
- Working in 3-week agile sprint to develop/test/deploy New Features/Bugs/Tech Improvement tickets
- Also involved in estimation and requirement planning on the same
- Addressing the customer experiences through SNOW as part of production support
- As part of production support, involved in extensive data analysis and building the data trends to improve the business
- Currently leading a team of 3 interns and got them to speed related to project activities.

Walt Disney[08/2020 - 11/2021]

- Involved in a team where we have successfully migrated the native dormitory application to AWS cloud
- Built a user interface for dormitory application where customers can upload and download the service agreement documents
- Worked in a 2-week agile sprint to develop/test/deploy production bugs
- Also involved in estimation and requirement planning on the same
- Learnt AWS tools such as Amazon S3, Param Store and Cloud Watch.